Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
당신이 한 일을 말했고
다들 이해했어요
Someone knows what you did at the prison.
They accepted.
그럴 필요까진 없어요
You don't have to.
아니에요 해야해요
No, they do.
당신한테 큰 빚을 졌어
I owe you everything.
내가 당신을 내보냈었지만
이젠 우리가 당신에게 합류하고 싶어
I sent you away and now we're joining you.
그래도 될까?
Will you have us?
- 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
- 나도 잘 모르겠어
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
쟤들이 베스를 데려갔었어!
They got Beth!
어서 차에 타
Come on, get in.
(engine starts)
♪ Good Lord, take my hand ♪
♪ I've dried up
this promised land ♪
♪ Afraid that the sun
won't rise for me... ♪
(crying)
♪ Good Lord, hear my cries ♪
♪ I've run out of wasted time ♪
♪ Dead just floating
out to sea... ♪
(snarling)
저기 가!
Go away!
♪ 'Cause I got
bad blood... ♪
제발 좀 꺼져!
Go away!
(car engine starts)
(tires screech)
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Good Lord, find my soul ♪
♪ Waiting to be whole ♪
♪ Hold those gates if I don't
make it out tonight... ♪
♪ Good Lord, give me peace ♪
- (rattles)
- ♪ Good Lord, give me peace ♪
♪ From a lifelong
of pain and greed ♪
♪ But not yet,
I'm not done paying ♪
♪ For my crimes ♪
♪ Bad blood ♪
♪ I got bad blood ♪
♪ You don't want none ♪
♪ Of what I have ♪
♪ Don't listen
to any word I say ♪
♪ I'd say anything
to make you feel okay ♪
♪ I'm not who I thought I was ♪
♪ Not today ♪
♪ 'Cause I got bad blood ♪
♪ Bad blood ♪
♪ You don't want none ♪
♪ Of what I have. ♪
한글자막 워키토끼
(theme music playing)
수정 금지 / 배포 제한
상업적 이용 금지
본 저작물의 저작권은 원저작권자 미국 AMC와 FOX사에 있습니다
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
그래서 그 이후론
베스와 함께 다녔던거야?
So it was just
you and Beth after?
- 그래
- 당신이 지켜줬고?
- Daryl: Yeah.
- You save her?
강한 애야
자신을 잘 지켰어
She's tough.
She saved herself.
한 동안은 밖에서 지냈지
We were out there for a while.
그러다 위험한 상황에 몰려서
먼저 내보냈는데...
We got cornered, she got out
in front of me and...
그러곤 잘 모르겠어 사라져버렸어
I don't know, she was gone.
나와보니 하얀 십자가가 창문에 붙어있는
I came out
and a car's pulling out
차 한대가 떠나고 있더라고
with a white cross
on the window.
- 저것처럼?
- 응
- Just like that one?
- Yep.
(snarling)
릭이 우리를 찾을거야
Daryl: Rick's gonna
wonder where we went.
연료가 얼마 안 남았어
Tank's runnin' low.
그냥 빨리 쫓아가서
빨리 해결하면 되잖아
We can end this quick.
Just run him off the road.
아니 아직이야
Nah, we're good for a bit.
놈들이 베스를 어딘가 데리고 있다면
저 놈한테서 알아낼 수 있을거야
If they're holding her somewhere,
we can get it out of the driver.
그래 근데 놈이 말을 안 하면
다시 처음부터 알아내야 돼
Yeah, but if he don't talk,
we're back to square one.
지금은 우리가 유리한 상황이야
Right now we got the advantage.
그러니까 한번 알아 보자구
We'll see who they are.
그룹이 더 있는지
뭘 할 수 있는지 확인하고
If they're a group,
see what they can do.
베스를 꼭 다시 데려와야지
And then we'll do what we
gotta do to get her back.
북쪽으로 가고 있어
I-85를 탔어
They're heading north,
I-85.
(walker snarling)
대체 뭘 기다리는거지?
What the hell's he waiting for?
두명이군
There's two of 'em.
경찰인건가?
Is that a cop?
발각됐을 수도 있으니까
They might've seen us.
(snarling)
(sighs)
(thudding)
(snarling, thudding continue)
(car engine sputters)
이런 젠장!
연료가 바닥났어
Aw, shit!
Tank's tapped.
우회로를 탈 수 있었는데 안탔다는 건
They'd have taken the
bypass and they didn't.
도시 어딘가에 숨어있단걸 거야
They must be holed up
in the city somewhere.
(walkers snarling)
움직이자, 동 틀 때까지
숨을 곳을 찾아야 해
We gotta move, find someplace
to hole up till sunlight.
한 두 블럭 거리에
내가 아는 곳이 한군데 있어
I know a place just a
couple of blocks from here.
거기로 가면 될거야
We can make it.
- (flesh squelches)
- (rapid tapping)
- 두 놈 더 와
- 거의 다 됐어
- Two more.
- I almost got it.
(walkers snarling)
어서 들어가자
Come on.
(walkers snarling)
여기서 일이라도 한거야?
You used to work here
or something?
일 한 건 아니야
Something.
(doorknob rattles)
(mutters)
- 뭐하는 곳이야?
- 쉼터 같은 곳이야
- Daryl: What's this place?
- It's temporary housing.
여기 왔었어?
You came here?
오래 머무르진 않았어
We didn't stay.
내가 이층을 쓸게
I'll take the top bunk.
아랫층은 당신이 좋아할 거 같네
I think that one's
more your style.
(chuckles)
지금은 자 둬
내가 먼저 망을 볼테니
You should sleep.
I'll take first watch.
- 꽤나 잘 잠겨있잖아
- 그건 알아
- This is locked up pretty tight.
- I know.
그럼 된거 아닌가
Then we're good, then.
상관없어
그래도 망을 볼거야
I'll keep first watch.
I don't mind.
좋을 대로 해
Suit yourself.
우리 다시 시작하자고 했었지?
You said we get to start over.
그래
Yeah.
진심이야?
Did you?
노력중이야
I'm tryin'.
정말 하고 싶은 말이 뭐야?
Why don't you say
what's really on your mind?
난 우리가 더 이상 사람들을
구하려 하지 않는 것 같아
I don't think we get
to save people anymore.
그럼 여기 왜 온 거야?
Then why are you here?
노력하는거지 나도
I'm tryin'.
차 옆에서 마주쳤을 때...
When we were out by the car...
내가 없었다면 어떻게 했을거야?
what if I didn't show up?
모르겠어
I still don't know.
(distant banging)
(snarling)
그러지 않아도 돼
You don't have to.
그럴필요 없대도
You don't.
(birds chirping)
고마워
Thank you.
저 차는 시내쪽으로 향했어
Daryl: That car was
headed downtown.
높은 곳에 자리를 잡아서
I say we get up
in one of the tall ones,
시야를 확보하면
더 자세히 볼 수 있을거야
get ourselves a view,
see what we see.
근처 빌딩에서 지켜본다고해도
We can stay close to the
buildings and keep quiet,
곧 행동에 옮겨야 할거야
but sooner or later,
we're gonna be drawing 'em.
(walkers snarling)
(snarling)
좋아, 저리 올라가 보자
All right, we can get up there.
다리가 있어
There's a bridge.
(snarling continues)
(snarls)
(walkers snarling)
가끔은 나도 뭐가 뭔질 모르겠다
Some days, I don't know
what the hell to think.
아침을 안먹어서 다행이야
Good thing we skipped breakfast.
(whistles)
결국엔 여기까지 왔네?
How did we get here?
음
Mm-mm.
그래
We just did.
내게 어떤 일이 있었는지
궁금하지도 않아?
You still haven't
asked me what happened.
타이리스와 애들을 만나고...
After I met up
with Tyreese, the girls.
이미 알고있어
Yeah, I know what happened.
이젠 지난 일이야
They ain't here.
그리 단순치 않았어
It was worse than that.
우리가 다시 시작할 수 있다고
내가 말했던 건...
The reason I said
we get to start over...
우리가 그렇게 할 수 있기 때문이야
is because we gotta.
그 과정이 쉽지 않아도...
The way it was...
그래
Yeah.
뭔가 보이는게 있어?
You see something?
아직은 안보여
라이플을 줘 봐
I don't know.
Hand me that rifle.
저쪽을 봐
Right there.
꽤 된것 같은데
It's been there a while.
한 패일거야
Definitely one of 'em.
분명히 연관이 있어
It's definitely
some kind of lead.
이제 물을 채워 놔야겠어
We should fill up.
그래
All right.
Hmm.
뭔데?
What?
어느 부자가 비싸게 주고 샀을거야
I bet this cost some rich
prick a lot of money.
개가 페인트 칠 위에 앉아서
Looks like a dog sat in paint,
여기저기 부벼놓은 거 같네
wiped its ass
all over the place.
그래?
난 마음에 드는데
Really?
I kinda like it.
그만해 됐어
(laughs)
Stop.
진짜야
I'm serious.
잘 알지도 못하면서
You don't know me.
그래 뭐,
계속 그렇게 말한다면야
Yep, you keep
tellin' yourself that.
(walkers snarling)
- 데릴 나오지마
- 일어나
- Daryl, don't.
- Get up.
손 올려
당신들 둘다
Hands up, both of you.
석궁 내려놔
Lay down your crossbow.
실수 하는거야
You got some sack on you.
이봐
아무도 다칠 필요 없어
Look, nobody has to get hurt.
난 그저 무기가 필요한 것 뿐이야
I just need weapons, that's it.
그러니까
그 석궁 좀 내려놓지 그래
So, please, lay down
your crossbow.
물러나
Back up.
이렇게까지 해서 미안하지만
- Sorry about this.
- (walker snarling)
당신들은 강해보이니까
You look tough.
별 다른 문제 없을거야
You'll be all right.
(snarling)
(gunshot)
(door closes)
(chains rattle)
세 발 남았어
Three bullets.
도시 한가운에 있는데
무기를 가져가 버리다니
We're in the middle of a city.
He was stealing our weapons.
내가 그를 죽이려 했다고 생각해?
Did you think
I was gonna kill him?
녀석의 다리를 겨누고 있었어
I was aiming for his leg.
다리를 쐈다면 죽었을까?
그랬을지도 모르지
Could that have killed him?
Maybe, I don't know.
근데 중요한 건
우리 무기를 훔쳐가는 놈이었잖아
But he was stealing our weapons.
그냥 애일 뿐이야
He's a damn kid.
무기가 없다면
우린 죽을지도 몰라
Without weapons we could die.
베스도 죽을거야
Beth could die.
무기는 찾으면 돼
We'll find more weapons.
난 당신이 죽는게 싫어
베스가 죽는것도 싫고
I don't want you to die.
I don't want Beth to die.
성당에 있는 그 누가
죽게 되는 것도 싫어
I don't want anybody
at the church to die,
그렇다고 멀뚱히 지켜보고
있을 수도 없어
but I can't stand around
and watch it happen either.
견딜 수 없다고
그래서 내가 떠났던거야
I can't.
That's why I left.
그래서 다른 곳을 찾았던거야
I just had to be somewhere else.
당신은 지금 다른 곳이 아니라
이렇게 여기에 있잖아
Well, you ain't somewhere
else; you're right here.
노력한다면서
Tryin'.
당신도 변한것 처럼
나도 이전의 내가 아니야
Look, you're not who you
were and neither am I.
(exhales)
더 이상 신이나 천국 같은 건 믿는지 모르겠어
I don't know if I believe
in God anymore or heaven,
하지만 내가 지옥에 가게 된다면
뭐 그건 확실해
but if I'm going to hell,
I'm making damn sure
안 가려고 최대한 버틸거야
I'm holding it off
as long as I can.
(items clatter)
(door opens)
좋아, 어디한번 끝장을 볼까
All right, let's get this done.
흔들리는것 같아
내가 가벼우니까 내가 볼게
It's not stable.
I'm lighter.
(grunts)
(snarling)
(Carol grunts)
(rattling)
(walkers snarling)
더 몰려와
There's more coming.
지금 뚫고 가야해
We're gonna
have to fight through.
그래 나도 보여
Yeah, I see 'em.
- 지금 나가야해
- GMH, 이게 뭐지 병원인가?
- We have to go.
- GMH, what's that? A hospital?
나도 잘 모르겠어
아마도 그래디 메모리얼이지 않을까?
I don't know.
Grady Memorial, maybe?
그래디? 여기야, 흰 십자가가 있는
아마 여기에 있을거야
Grady, the white crosses-- it
might be where they're holing up.
(snarling)
데릴!
- Carol: Daryl!
- (knife piercing)
가, 어서 가!
Daryl:
Go, go, go, go!
(knife piercing)
쓸만한 거 뭐 없어?
Anything we can use?
아무것도 없어
Nothin' but what we got.
좋아, 벨트 잘 매
Daryl:
All right, buckle up.
(snarling)
잘 붙잡고 있어
You hold on.
(snarling continues faintly)
이제 괜찮아
- (Daryl groans)
- We're okay.
이제 괜찮아
We're okay.
(bodies thudding)
이런
God.
(groans)
뭐지
Ow.
(walker snarling)
물 여깄어
Here.
난 괜찮아
I'm fine.
마셔봐 그럼
Prove it.
얼마나 안좋은거야?
How bad is it?
더 심한 일도 있었는데 뭘
I've had worse.
바보같은 시도였어
Damn, that was stupid.
그래도 잘 내려왔잖아
We made good time down.
(scoffs)
여기서 병원까진
딱 세 블럭 정도야
There's only three blocks
between us and Grady.
스코프로 자세히 확인할 수 있을 만한
We need to find a place nearby,
장소를 근처에서 찾아야 해
scope it out,
see what we can see.
그냥 단순히 보는걸로
You really think we're gonna
find out what we need to know
찾을 수 있을거라고 생각해?
just by watching?
그것부터 해야지 별수 있나
It's where we start.
가자
Come on.
(snarling weakly)
(snarling stops)
놈들이야
It's them.
잘됐네
All right.
이제 한번 살펴보자고
Let's see what we see.
(crunching)
내가 예전 같지 않다고 했지?
You said I ain't like
how I was before?
그랬지
Yeah.
예전엔 어땠는데?
How was I?
그떈 마냥 애 같았는데
It's like you were a kid.
이젠 남자가 됐어
Now you're a man.
그럼 당신 얘기는?
What about you?
나는 소피아와 쉼터에
하루 반나절 정도 있었어
Me and Sophia stayed at that
shelter for a day and a half
그리고 다시 에드에게 돌아갔지
before I went
running back to Ed.
집에 돌아가니 폭력이 일상이 됐고
I went home, I got
beat up, life went on,
그저 기적이 일어나게 해달라고 기도했어
and I just kept praying
for something to happen.
그 외엔 아무것도 하지 않았어
But I didn't do anything.
아무것도 말야
Not a damn thing.
그의 곁에 있던 나는...
Who I was with him...
불에 타버렸어
she got burned away.
그 사실이 행복했어
아니, 행복까진 아니더라도...
And I was happy about that.
I mean, not happy, but...
그리고 교도소에선
And at the prison
내가 바라던 모습을 찾고 싶었어
I got to be who I always
thought I should be,
내가 보였어야 하는 내 모습
thought I should've been.
그런데 그 모습도 불에 타버렸지
And then she got burned away.
그리고 이제는...
Everything now just...
당신에게 묶여있어
consumes you.
글쎄...
Well, hey...
우린 이렇게 살아있잖아
we ain't ashes.
(distant door closes)
(thudding)
(walker snarling)
(thudding continues)
(snarling continues)
당신 화살이야?
Is that yours?
맞아
Yeah.
- (automatic gunfire)
- (walker snarling)
(yelling)
이런 세상에
(groans)
Oh, God.
괜찮아
I'm good.
난 괜찮으니까
어서 가봐
I'm good.
You go.
세상에
God.
(panting)
(man grunting)
- (snarling)
- (groaning, gasping)
제, 제발요
그땐 어쩔 수 없었어요
Plea-- please.
I had to protect myself.
- 왜 우릴 따라다니는거지?
-그, 그런적 없어요, 맹세해요! 전 당신들이 따라오는줄 알았어요
- Why you followin' us?
- I-I didn't, I swear! I thought you followed me.
웃기지마
Bullshit.
(walker continues snarling)
이봐요 제발
부, 부탁이에요!
Noah: Come on, man.
Plea-- please!
(groans)
- 제발요 이렇게 부탁드릴게요
- 아니, 이미 한번 살려줬어
- Please, please.
- Nah, I already helped you once.
다신 그런 일 없을거야
It ain't happenin' again.
(walker continues snarling)
그럼 한번 재밌게 놀아보라고
Have fun with Hoss over there.
안돼요 안돼
Noah:
No. No, no, no.
안돼요!
제발요! 제발!
No. No, no, no!
Please! Please!
제발요!
죄송했어요, 한번만요!
Please!
I'm sorry, please!
- 부탁이에요 제발요!
- 데릴 이제 그만해
- Please! Please, please!
- Daryl. Daryl. Stop.
당신도 이 자식 때문에 죽을뻔 했잖아!
You almost died 'cause of him!
그래 하지만 안죽었잖아
But I didn't.
아니, 그냥 내버려 둬
Nah, let him be.
- 죄송합니다 정말 죄송했어요!
- 데릴!
- Noah: I'm sorry. Please, I'm sorry!
- Daryl!
(yelling)
(snarling)
(grunting)
좀만 더
Come on, just a little more.
감사합니다 정말 감사해요
감사합니다
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
(panting)
괜찮은거야?
Daryl:
You okay?
당신은 괜찮아?
여기 이렇게 있잖아
I'm still here.
가야겠어요
가봐야겠어
I gotta go.
그들이 올 거예요
총성을 들었을거예요
They're gonna come.
They probably heard the shot.
만약에 저들이 날 찾으면...
If they find me...
- 누굴 말하는거야?
- 저 사람들이요, 병원에 있는 사람들요
- Who?
- Them, people at the hospital.
잠깐만 잠깐만 너 지금...
혹시 저기에 금발의 소녀가 있지 않았어?
Wait, wait, wait, just tell us--
is there a blonde girl there?
- 금발을 봤지?
- 베스요?
- You see a blonde girl?
- Beth?
베스를 알아요?
You know her?
베스가 제가 탈출하도록 도와줬는데
걔는 아직 안에 있어요
She helped me get out,
but she's still there.
놈들이 왔어
They're coming.
이제 가야되요
빠져나가야 해요
We gotta go now. We gotta go.
We gotta go.
옆 건물에 지하가 있어요
The building next door
has a basement.
거긴 아무것도 없으니 안전할거예요
It's clear.
We'll be safe.
Ah! Ah!
가, 내가 부축할게
Daryl:
Go, I got him.
어서 일어나
Come on, get up.
- 일어나 봐
- 알겠어요
- Get up.
- (groans) Okay.
(tires screech)
안돼 안돼 안돼요!
기다려요 기다려!
No, no, no!
Wait, wait, wait!
- 이거 놔!
- 기다려봐요! 저들이 도울 수 있어요
- Let go of me!
- Wait! They can help her.
지금은 저들만이 그녀를 도울 수 있어요
They're the only ones who can.
약, 의료기구, 의사까지 갖췄으니까요
They have medicine,
machines, a doctor.
당신이 저기로 나가면
저 사람들을 죽일거잖아요?
You go out there,
you'll have to kill them, okay?
그러면 저 분은 치료를 받지 못할거라구요
그랬으면 좋겠어요?
And then she can't get their help.
Is that what you want?
(panting)
우리가 다시 데려올 수 있어요
베스도 다시 데려올 수 있구요
We can get her back.
We can get Beth back.
그럼 뭐가 필요한데?
What's it gonna take?
많이요
A lot.
저들은 총도 있고 사람들도 있어요
They got guns, people.
그건 우리도 마찬가지야
So do we.
(snarling)